Guide to the Jewish Labor Committee Records, Part II WAG.025.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Administrative and Organizational Records
  - Subseries I:C: Correspondence
    - Other Organizations
      - Jewish Labor Bund, 1948-1956 (Box 59, Folder 43)
      - Jewish-Lithuanian Cultural Society "Lite", 1951-1953 (Box 59, Folder 44)
        Microfilm reel#: 183
      - Jewish Information Bureau, 1949-1952 (Box 59, Folder 45)
      - Jewish National Workers Alliance, 1948-1956 (Box 59, Folder 46)
      - Jewish Occupational Council, 1948-1956 (Box 59, Folder 47)
      - Jewish Socialist Verband of America, 1948-1956 (Box 59, Folder 48)
      - Jewish Telegraphic Agency, 1948-1956 (Box 59, Folder 49)
      - Jewish War Veterans, 1951-1956 (Box 59, Folder 50)
      - Jewish World News Service, 1948 (Box 59, Folder 51)
      - Jewish Writers Union, 1951-1956 (Box 59, Folder 52)
      - Jews from France, Inc., 1948-1949 (Box 59, Folder 53)
      - Joint Committee on Population Trends, undated (Box 59, Folder 54)
      - Katzetler Farband, 1951-1952 (Box 59, Folder 55)
      - KZ: American Association of Former Inmates..., 1949 (Box 59, Folder 56)
      - Labor Committee to Release Imprisoned Trade Unionists, 1955-1956 (Box 59, Folder 57)
      - Labor League for Human Rights, 1948 (Box 59, Folder 58)
      - Landsmanshaftn, 1948-1954 (Box 59, Folder 59)
      - League for Industrial Democracy, 1948-1951 (Box 60, Folder 1)
      - League for Industrial Democracy, 1952 (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - League for Industrial Democracy, 1954-1956 (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - Left Poale Zion, 1948-1956 (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Liberal Party, 1950, 1954-1956 (Box 60, Folder 5)
        Microfilm reel#: 184
      - Manhattan Jewish Conference, 1952 (Box 60, Folder 6)
      - National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board, 1948-1949 (Box 60, Folder 7)
      - National Committee for Labor Israel, 1949-1956 (Box 60, Folder 8)
      - National Committee to Repeal the McCarren Acts, 1948-1954 (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - National Committee on Immigration Policy, 1948-1949 (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - National Consumers League, 1952 (Box 60, Folder 11)
      - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1952-1953 (Box 60, Folder 12)
      - National Conference on Internatinal Economic and Social Development, 1952 (Box 60, Folder 13)
      - National Jewish Welfare Board, 1948-1956 (Box 60, Folder 14)
      - National Religion and Labor Foundation, 1948-1952 (Box 60, Folder 15)
      - National Sharecroppers Fund, 1951-1952, 1956 (Box 60, Folder 16)
      - National Trade Union Council, 1956 (Box 60, Folder 17)
      - Negro Labor Committee, 1952 (Box 60, Folder 18)
      - New York Women's Trade Union League, 1952 (Box 60, Folder 19)
      - Orthodox Organizations, 1948-1949 (Box 60, Folder 20)
      - Peretz Writers Union, 1948-1949 (Box 60, Folder 21)
      - Poale Zion, 1953 (Box 60, Folder 22)
      - Polish Democratic Party in Exile, 1950-1951 (Box 60, Folder 23)
      - Post War World Council, 1949 (Box 60, Folder 24)
      - Rescue Fund for Jewish Refugee Writers, 1948-1949 (Box 60, Folder 25)
      - Roumanian Labor League, Jan 1948-Jun 1948 (Box 60, Folder 26)
      - Roumanian Labor League, Jul 1948-Dec 1948 (Box 60, Folder 27)
      - Roumanian Labor League, 1949 (Box 60, Folder 28)
      - Roumanian Labor League, 1950 (Box 60, Folder 29)
        Microfilm reel#: 185
      - Roumanian Labor League, 1951 (Box 60, Folder 30)
      - Roumanian Labor League, 1952-1953 (Box 60, Folder 31)
      - Social Democratic Federation, 1948-1955 (Box 60, Folder 32)
      - Socialist Party, 1952-1953 (Box 60, Folder 33)
      - Socialist Union of Central-Eastern Europe, 1956 (Box 60, Folder 34)
      - Spanish Refugee Aid, 1954 (Box 60, Folder 35)
      - Union for the Protection of the Human Person, 1948-1952 (Box 60, Folder 36)
      - Union of Russian Jews, 1948-1953 (Box 60, Folder 37)
      - Unions: General, 1948-1951 (Box 60, Folder 38)
      - Unions: General, 1952 (Box 60, Folder 39)
      - Unions: General, 1953-1956 (Box 60, Folder 40)
      - Unions: Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1948-1956 (Box 60, Folder 41)
      - Unions: Hebrew Actors Union, 1948-1956 (Box 60, Folder 42)
      - Unions: ILGWU, 1948-1950 (Box 60, Folder 43)
      - Unions: ILGWU, 1951-1952 (Box 60, Folder 44)
        Microfilm reel#: 186
      - Unions: ILGWU, 1953-1956 (Box 60, Folder 45)
      - Unions: ILGWU, Joint Board...Cloakmakers, 1948-1953 (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - Unions: ILGWU, Joint Board...Dressmakers, 1948-1956 (Box 61, Folder 2)
      - Unions: ILGWU, Locals, 1948 (Box 61, Folder 3)
      - Unions: ILGWU, Locals, 1949-1951 (Box 61, Folder 4)
      - Unions: ILGWU, Locals, 1952-1956 (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Unions: OPEIU, Locals 153, 1948-1956 (Box 61, Folder 6)
      - Unions: Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union, 1951 (Box 61, Folder 7)
      - Unions: Teachers Guild, 1950-1951 (Box 61, Folder 8)
      - Unions: United Hatters, Cap & Millinery Workers Union, 1949-1956 (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - United Galician Jews, 1951 (Box 61, Folder 10)
      - United Hebrew Trades, 1948-1956 (Box 61, Folder 11)
      - United Jewish Appeal, 1948-1956 (Box 61, Folder 12)
      - United Jewish Survivors of Nazi Persecution, 1951-1955 (Box 61, Folder 13)
      - United Pruziner Relief, 1948-1955 (Box 61, Folder 14)
      - United Vilner Relief Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 61, Folder 15)
      - Workmen's Circle, 1954-1956 (Box 61, Folder 16)
        Microfilm reel#: 187
      - Workers Defense League, 1954-1956 (Box 61, Folder 17)
      - World Congress for Jewish Culture, 1948 (Box 61, Folder 18)
      - World Jewish Congress, 1948-1949, 1956 (Box 61, Folder 19)
      - Yiddish Art Theatre Society, 1948-1949 (Box 61, Folder 20)
      - Yiddish Pen Club, 1952, 1956 (Box 61, Folder 21)
      - Zionist Organizations (USA), 1948-1956 (Box 61, Folder 22)
  - Subseries I:D: Meetings, Conferences and Other Events
    - Boehm - Maisel Luncheon, Jul 14, 1948 (Box 61, Folder 23)
    - Carusi Luncheon, Jul 29, 1948 (Box 61, Folder 24)
    - Dinner to Discuss Displaced Persons Act, Oct 27, 1948 (Box 61, Folder 25)
    - Vladeck Memorial: I, Nov 14, 1948 (Box 61, Folder 26)
    - Vladeck Memorial: II, Nov 14, 1948 (Box 61, Folder 27)
    - Vladeck Memorial: III, Nov 14, 1948 (Box 61, Folder 28)
    - National Staff Conference, Mar 6, 1950Mar 10, 1950 (Box 61, Folder 29)
    - Meeting with Workmen's Circle Secretaries, Sep 6, 1950 (Box 61, Folder 30)
    - Labor Conference to Stop Communist Aggression: I, Oct 1, 1950 (Box 61, Folder 31)
    - Labor Conference to Stop Communist Aggression: II, Oct 1, 1950 (Box 61, Folder 32)
    - William Green Testimonial: I, Oct 28, 1951 (Box 61, Folder 33)
    - William Green Testimonial: II, Oct 28, 1951 (Box 61, Folder 34)
      Microfilm reel#: 188
    - William Green Testimonial: III, Oct 28, 1951 (Box 61, Folder 35)
    - Moch-Schaerf Luncheon, Mar 19, 1952 (Box 61, Folder 36)
    - Atran Center: Opening of Atran Jewish Culture House, May 11, 1952 (Box 61, Folder 37)
    - Peretz Square: Dedication, Nov 23, 1952 (Box 61, Folder 38)
    - Prague Protest Meeting: I, Dec 21, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Prague Protest Meeting: II, Dec 21, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Prague Protest Meeting: III, Dec 21, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Rally Against Soviet Anti-Semitism, Feb 6, 1953 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Philip Murray: Dedication of Bust, Feb 16, 1953 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Vladeck-Liesin Memorial, Dec 20, 1953 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Conference of Jewish Organizations, Mar 6, 1955 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Rally in Support of Israel, Nov 15, 1955 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Conference of Jewish Organizations (Washington, D.C.), Jan 17, 1956Jan 18, 1956 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Public Trial: Soviet Anti-Semitism, Apr 30, 1956 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Conference on Hungary, Middle East and Soviet Deportations, Nov 29, 1956 (Box 62, Folder 11)
      Microfilm reel#: 189
  - Subseries I:E: General Files.
    - Abraham Cahan Fund for Labor Veterans, 1951 (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - Abraham Cahan Fund for Labor Veterans, 1952-1955 (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - Affiliates: JLC, 1951 (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - AFL-CIO Unity Convention, 1955 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Aid: Clothing, 1948-1950, 1956 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - Aid: Employment, 1948-1952 (Box 62, Folder 17)
    - Aid: Food, 1948-1954 (Box 62, Folder 18)
    - Aid: General, 1948-1949 (Box 62, Folder 19)
    - Aid: Individual, 1950-1953 (Box 62, Folder 20)
    - American Jewish Tercentenary, 1954-1955 (Box 62, Folder 21)
    - Anti-Communism, 1946-1951 (Box 62, Folder 22)
    - Anti-Communism, 1952-1956 (Box 62, Folder 23)
      Microfilm reel#: 190
    - Anti-Semitism, 1948-1956 (Box 62, Folder 24)
    - Archives at JLC Warehouse, 1953 (Box 62, Folder 25)
    - Atran Center, 1949-1953 (Box 62, Folder 26)
    - Atran, Frank Z., 1950-1953 (Box 62, Folder 27)
    - Aufbau, 1948-1955 (Box 62, Folder 28)
    - Austrian Refugees, 1949 (Box 62, Folder 29)
    - Bank Records, 1948 (Box 62, Folder 30)
    - Baskin, Joseph, 1948-1952 (Box 62, Folder 31)
    - Blum, Leon, 1948-1950 (Box 62, Folder 32)
    - Blumin-Kursky, Maximilian, 1950-1951 (Box 62, Folder 33)
    - Book Fund, 1948-1953 (Box 62, Folder 34)
    - Camp Eden, 1948-1952 (Box 62, Folder 35)
    - Cargo for Children Campaign, 1948-1949 (Box 62, Folder 36)
    - Circulars, 1948 (Box 62, Folder 37)
    - Clothing Campaign: New York, 1948 (Box 62, Folder 38)
    - Clothing Campaign: Out of Town, 1948 (Box 62, Folder 39)
    - Committee to Combat Anti-Semitism, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 40)
    - Communism (U.S.), 1948-1953 (Box 62, Folder 41)
    - Communism (U.S.), 1954-1956 (Box 63, Folder 1)
      Microfilm reel#: 191
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims Against Germany, May 1956-Jun 1956 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims Against Germany, Jul 1956-Dec 1956 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Contact (newsletter), 1952 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Contributions, 1938 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Contributions, 1949-1950 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Contributions, 1951-1955 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Contributions/Dues, 1956 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Contributions ("Friends of the Jewish Labor Committee), 1953 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Contributions: Individuals, Jan 1948-Aug 1948 (Box 63, Folder 10)
      Microfilm reel#: 192
    - Contributions: Individuals, Sep 1948-Dec 1948 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Contributions: Individuals, 1951-1953 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Contributions: Organizations, 1951-1953 (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Countertide, 1951 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Cross-Section, U.S.A., by Allen Lesser, 1953 (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - Czech Refugees, 1948 (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - Czech Trials, 1952-1953 (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - Day (Der Tog), 1949, 1951-1953, 1956 (Box 63, Folder 18)
    - Displaced Persons, 1948 (Box 63, Folder 19)
    - Displaced Persons, 1949 (Box 63, Folder 20)
    - Displaced Persons, 1950-1951 (Box 63, Folder 21)
    - Displaced Persons: Tuberculosis, 1952 (Box 63, Folder 22)
    - East European Jewry, ca.1949 (Box 63, Folder 23)
    - Education Issues, 1951 (Box 63, Folder 24)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1955 (Box 63, Folder 25)
    - Employment: JLC, 1948 (Box 63, Folder 26)
    - Epstein, Melech, 1951 (Box 63, Folder 27)
    - Fact and Opinions, 1948-1951 (Box 63, Folder 28)
    - Fact and Opinions, 1952-1953 (Box 63, Folder 29)
    - Fact and Opinions, 1955-1956 (Box 63, Folder 30)
    - Fascism in America: Research File, undated (Box 63, Folder 31)
    - Feifel's Relief Committee, undated (Box 63, Folder 32)
      Microfilm reel#: 193
    - Field Staff, 1950-1952 (Box 63, Folder 33)
    - Finances, 1948-1950 (Box 63, Folder 34)
    - Finances, 1951-1953 (Box 63, Folder 35)
    - Finances, 1954-1956 (Box 63, Folder 36)
    - Fisk University, 1951-1952 (Box 63, Folder 37)
    - "For America" Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 63, Folder 38)
    - Free Voice of Labor, 1948-1956 (Box 63, Folder 39)
    - Friedman Script, 1952 (Box 63, Folder 40)
    - Friends of the Jewish Labor Committee, 1953 (Box 63, Folder 41)
    - Fundraising Campaign, 1951 (Box 63, Folder 42)
    - Gebiner, Benjamin, 1948-1956 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Genocide, 1949-1951 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Genocide, 1952-1956 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - German Affairs, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - German Socialists, 1948-1956 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Gliksman, Jerzy ("Tell the West"), 1948 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Goldstein, Bernard ("The Stars Bear Witness"), 1949 (Box 64, Folder 7)
      Microfilm reel#: 194
    - Grade, Chaim: Tour, 1949 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Grossman, Cyrus (Bronx River Community Center), 1955 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Gutgold: Tour, 1948 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Handbook on Shop Problems, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Hebrew University, 1949-1956 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - History of Jewish Teachers in Poland, 1950-1951 (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Human Rights, 1947-1948 (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Human Rights, 1949-1951 (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1950 (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - Hungarian-American Press, 1948 (Box 64, Folder 17)
    - Hungarian Project: General, 1954-1956 (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - Hungarian Project: Radio Free Europe, 1956-1957 (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - Hungarian Project: Robert Major Manuscript, 1956 (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - Hungarian Project: Robert Major Notes, ca.1956 (Box 64, Folder 21)
    - Hungary: Crusade for Freedom Campaign, 1956 (Box 64, Folder 22)
    - Hungary - Deportations, 1951-1952 (Box 64, Folder 23)
    - In Review, 1948 (Box 64, Folder 24)
    - Indemnification for Individuals, undated (Box 64, Folder 25)
    - Informational Media Guarantee Program: Books for Israel, 1951-1953 (Box 64, Folder 26)
    - Institute for American Democracy, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 27)
      Microfilm reel#: 195
    - Institute for Democratic Education, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 28)
    - Integrity of Citizenship, 1956 (Box 64, Folder 29)
    - International Institute for Social History, 1955 (Box 64, Folder 30)
    - Iraq: Jews, 1949 (Box 64, Folder 31)
    - Israel Embassy, 1956 (Box 64, Folder 32)
    - Jewish Daily Forward, 1948-1949 (Box 64, Folder 33)
    - Jewish Daily Forward, 1950-1956 (Box 64, Folder 34)
    - "Jewish Labor Committee in Action at Home and Abroad", 1948 (Box 64, Folder 35)
    - Jewish Labor Fights Communism, 1950-1951 (Box 64, Folder 36)
    - Jewish Libraries (Europe), 1951 (Box 64, Folder 37)
    - Jewish Morning Journal, 1951-1952, 1956 (Box 64, Folder 38)
    - Jewish Newsletter, 1951-1953 (Box 64, Folder 39)
    - Jewish Press - World Wide, 1956 (Box 64, Folder 40)
    - Jewish Teachers Seminary, 1948, 1951-1953, 1956 (Box 64, Folder 41)
    - Jews Behind the Iron Curtain, 1949 (Box 64, Folder 42)
    - Jews Behind the Iron Curtain, 1950-1951 (Box 64, Folder 43)
    - JLC News Clips, 1956 (Box 64, Folder 44)
      Microfilm reel#: 196
    - JLC Outlook, 1954-1956 (Box 64, Folder 45)
    - Karl Family, 1949-1953 (Box 64, Folder 46)
    - Karl Fund, 1952-1955 (Box 64, Folder 47)
    - Katznelson Institute, 1950-1951 (Box 64, Folder 48)
    - Kinder Journal, 1948-1949, 1951-1953, 1956 (Box 64, Folder 49)
    - Labor Aid Project, 1948-1952 (Box 64, Folder 50)
    - Labor Aid Project, 1953-1956 (Box 64, Folder 51)
    - Labor and Nation, 1949-1954 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Labor Day Greetings, 1948-1949 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Labor in Exile (newspaper), 1953 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Labor Press: Lists, undated (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Labor Reports, 1951 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Labor Reports, 1952 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Labor Reports, 1955-1956 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Legislation, 1949 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Legislative Research and Information Bureau, 1949 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Lehman, Herbert, 1950-1956 (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Lichtenstein, Zalman, 1950-1953 (Box 65, Folder 11)
      Microfilm reel#: 197
    - Lists: Committees, etc., 1951 (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Luncheons, 1949 (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - MacIver Report, 1951-1952 (Box 65, Folder 14)
    - Manger, Itzik - Jubilee Book Fund, 1952-1953 (Box 65, Folder 15)
    - Memos/Notices, 1952-1953 (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - Memos/Notices, 1956 (Box 65, Folder 17)
    - Middle East, 1956 (Box 65, Folder 18)
    - Milgram, Morris, 1956 (Box 65, Folder 19)
    - Minkoff, Isaiah, 1951-1952 (Box 65, Folder 20)
    - Minkoff, Nathaniel, 1948 (Box 65, Folder 21)
    - Minority Rights: Research Materials, undated (Box 65, Folder 22)
    - Mollet, Guy, 1955 (Box 65, Folder 23)
    - Morning Journal, 1948-1949 (Box 65, Folder 24)
    - Murray, Philip: death, 1952 (Box 65, Folder 25)
    - Naiman Claim, 1948 (Box 65, Folder 26)
    - National Executive Committee, 1948-1953 (Box 65, Folder 27)
    - National Jewish Conference, 1954 (Box 65, Folder 28)
    - National Labor Service, 1952 (Box 65, Folder 29)
    - Neue Volkszeitung, 1949 (Box 65, Folder 30)
    - New Leader, 1949-1956 (Box 65, Folder 31)
    - New School for Social Research, 1954 (Box 65, Folder 32)
    - Office Committee, 1948-1949, 1956 (Box 65, Folder 33)
    - Office for Jewish Population Research, 1949 (Box 65, Folder 34)
    - Office Staff, 1951-1953 (Box 65, Folder 35)
    - Overseas Delegation, 1949 (Box 65, Folder 36)
    - Passport and Visas, 1953-1954 (Box 65, Folder 37)
    - Picon, Molly and Kalich, Jacob, 1948 (Box 65, Folder 38)
      Microfilm reel#: 198
    - Pioneers of Labor: Reactions, 1951-1952 (Box 65, Folder 39)
    - Play: Script, undated (Box 65, Folder 40)
    - Poles in Wartime Soviet Union (report), 1948 (Box 65, Folder 41)
    - Police Department, NYC, 1956 (Box 65, Folder 42)
    - Press: Correspondence, 1952-1956 (Box 65, Folder 43)
    - Press Releases: English, 1948-1950 (Box 65, Folder 44)
    - Press Releases: English, 1951-1953 (Box 65, Folder 45)
    - Press Releases: English, 1954 (Box 65, Folder 46)
    - Press Releases: English, 1955 (Box 65, Folder 47)
    - Press Releases: English, 1956 (Box 65, Folder 48)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, 1948 (Box 65, Folder 49)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, Jan 1949-Jun 1949 (Box 65, Folder 50)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, Jul 1949-Dec 1949 (Box 65, Folder 51)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, 1951-1952 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      Microfilm reel#: 199
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, 1953-1954 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, 1955 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Press Releases: Yiddish, 1956 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - "Professional Women in World War II", 1951 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Publicity, 1948-1951 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Puerto Rico, 1950-1952 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Rabb, Maxwell, 1955-1956 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Racolin, Alexander, 1949-1952 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Racolin, Mendel, 1948-1949 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Radio Free Europe, 1956 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Rand School, 1948-1951 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Raskin, Jacob and Sophie, 1950-1956 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Recommendations, 1951-1954 (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - Reparations, 1951 (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - Reparations: Austria, 1953-1955 (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - Reports, undated, 1948 (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - Reports, 1949 (Box 66, Folder 18)
      Microfilm reel#: 200
    - Reports, 1950-1951 (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - Reports, 1952-1956 (Box 66, Folder 20)
    - Research Committee, 1951 (Box 66, Folder 21)
    - Right Wing Groups, 1951-1952 (Box 66, Folder 22)
    - Ringelblum Archive, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 23)
    - Romualdi, Serafino, 1952 (Box 66, Folder 24)
    - Rosenberg Case, 1952-1953 (Box 66, Folder 25)
    - Rosenwald, Lessing J., 1951-1956 (Box 66, Folder 26)
    - Rosh Hashana Greetings, 1948 (Box 66, Folder 27)
    - Roumania: Protest, 1955 (Box 66, Folder 28)
    - Rubinstein, Nina, 1952-1954 (Box 66, Folder 29)
    - Rule 22, 1958-1959 (Box 66, Folder 30)
    - Russian-Americans, 1956 (Box 66, Folder 31)
    - Russian Emigres, 1949, 1951-1954 (Box 66, Folder 32)
    - Russian Social Democrats, 1948-1949 (Box 66, Folder 33)
    - Sanders, Edith, 1952 (Box 66, Folder 34)
    - School for Workers, University of Wisconsin, 1949 (Box 66, Folder 35)
    - Seligman, Ben B.: Reports, Welfare Funds, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 36)
    - Semi-Monthly Survey of the Leading Foreign Language Press, 1948 (Box 66, Folder 37)
    - Sheehan, Hugh, 1952 (Box 66, Folder 38)
    - Soviet Jewry, 1949-1952 (Box 66, Folder 39)
    - Soviet Jewry, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 40)
      Microfilm reel#: 201
    - Soviet Jewry, 1954-1956 (Box 66, Folder 41)
    - Soviet Jewry: "Appeal to the Conscience of Mankind", 1951-1952 (Box 66, Folder 42)
    - Staff, JLC, 1948-1952 (Box 66, Folder 43)
    - Staff Meetings, 1952-1955 (Box 66, Folder 44)
    - Staff Memos, 1950-1953 (Box 66, Folder 45)
    - Stein, Fred, 1948 (Box 66, Folder 46)
    - Subversives, 1953-1956 (Box 66, Folder 47)
    - Subversives: Government Documents, 1948 (Box 66, Folder 48)
    - Subversives: Background File, undated (Box 66, Folder 49)
    - Tax Exemption, 1948 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - "To Rise Together": typescript, undated (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Trotsky, Leon: about, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - United Nations, 1948-1956 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - United Nations: Attacks on, 1952-1953 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - United States: Congress, 1949-1954 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - United States: Department of Labor, 1951-1952 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - United States: Department of State, 1948-1956 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - United States: Immigration & Naturalization Service, 1951-1952 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - United States: Presidents, 1948-1950 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - Unser Tsait, 1948-1949, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 11)
      Microfilm reel#: 202
    - Vladeck Home, 1948-1949 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Vladeck: manuscript, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Vladeck Memorial Fund, 1952 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Vlasov Movement, 1948 (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - Voice of America, 1953 (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - Voice of the Unconquered, 1948 (Box 67, Folder 17)
    - Wagner, Robert F., Jr., 1955 (Box 67, Folder 18)
    - Wallach, Sidney, 1948 (Box 67, Folder 19)
    - Walter White Memorial, Apr 3, 1955 (Box 67, Folder 20)
    - Warehouse Reports, 1948-1951 (Box 67, Folder 21)
    - Warsaw Ghetto Anniversary, 1954 (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - WEVD, 1949, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 23)
    - Who's Who in World Jewry, 1953-1954 (Box 67, Folder 24)
    - Workers Education Bureau, 1952 (Box 67, Folder 25)
    - Worthy, William - reports from Soviet Union, 1955-1956 (Box 67, Folder 26)
    - Yiddish Encyclopedia, 1948-1956 (Box 67, Folder 27)
    - Yiddisher Kemfer, 1954-1956 (Box 67, Folder 28)
    - Yiddish in Israel, 1951 (Box 67, Folder 29)
    - Yiddish Scientific Institute (YIVO), 1948-1952 (Box 67, Folder 30)
    - Yiddish Scientific Institute (YIVO), 1953-1956 (Box 67, Folder 31)
    - Zimmerman, Charles, 1952-1956 (Box 67, Folder 32)
    - Zuckerman, Jacob T., 1953-1955 (Box 67, Folder 33)
    - Zukunft, 1948-1949 (Box 67, Folder 34)
    - Zukunft, 1951-1956 (Box 67, Folder 35)
  - Subseries I:F: Women's Division Records, 1947-1956
    - Women's Division: Constitution & History, 1947, 1949, 1955 (Box 67, Folder 36)
      Microfilm reel#: 203
    - Women's Division: Agendas: Officers' Meetings, 1947-1948 (Box 67, Folder 37)
    - Women's Division: Minutes: Executive Committee, 1947-1952, 1954 (Box 67, Folder 38)
    - Women's Division: Minutes --Administrative Committee, 1951-1955 (Box 67, Folder 39)
    - Women's Division: Minutes - Manhattan Chapter, Bus. & Prof. Women, 1953-1956 (Box 67, Folder 40)
    - Women's Division: Correspondence, Jan 1947-Aug 1947 (Box 67, Folder 41)
    - Women's Division: Correspondence, Sep 1947-Dec 1947 (Box 67, Folder 42)
    - Women's Division: Correspondence, Jan 1948-Jun 1948 (Box 67, Folder 43)
    - Women's Division: Correspondence, Jul 1948-Dec 1948 (Box 67, Folder 44)